the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license
以下内容是根据Creative Commons授权提供
your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to offer
您的支持将有助于麻省理工学院开放式课程继续报价
high-quality educational resources for free
免费优质教育资源
to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of them IT
进行捐赠或查看附加材料由数百人资讯
courses
课程
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at 0 CW
参观麻省理工学院开放式课程在0 CW
that MIT ided you
麻省理工学院被提供的你
home
家
in
the norm
规范
are
有
the last lecture we discuss the number
我们讨论的号码的最后演讲
general properties for systems which
对系统的一般特性的
as you recall applied both to continuous-time
因为你还记得这两个应用到连续时间
and to discrete-time systems
和离散时间系统
and these properties were the properties
而这些特性是属性
associated with the system having memory the issue
该系统具有内存问题相关
love whether a system is or isn't convertible
爱一个系统是否是或不是可兑换
we talked about causality instability
我们谈到因果关系的不稳定性
and finally we talked about when the arity
最后我们谈到当元数
and time-invariant in today's lecture
时不变在今天的讲座
what I'd like to do is focused specifically on when the arity in time
我想要做的是专门针对当时间参数数量
invariance
不变性
and show how for systems that have those properties
并说明如何为具有这些属性系统
we can exploit them to generate
我们可以利用它们来生成
a general representation well let me begin by
一般的表示也让我首先
just reviewing the two properties again quickly
刚刚重新检讨两个属性迅速
time invariance as you recall
你记得时间不变性
is a property that apply both to continuous-time and discrete-time
是同时适用于连续时间和离散时间的属性
systems
系统
and in essence stated bad for any given
并且在本质上说坏对于任何给定
input and output relationship if we
输入和输出的关系，如果我们
simply shift the input than the output shift by the same amount
简单地以相同的量移位的输入比输出移
and of course exactly the same kind of statement
当然完全相同的语句种类
applied in discrete-time so it i mean variance was a property
在离散时间应用，因此我的意思是方差的性质
it said that the system didn't care about what the time origin
它说，该系统并没有在意时间原点是什么
the signal is when the arity
该信号是元数时，
was a property related to the fact that if we have
是相关的事实的属性，如果我们有
et cetera outputs associated with a given set of inputs
与一组给定的输入相关联等等输出
as i've indicated here with the inputs
因为我已经在这里表示与投入
as feasted K and the output decisive K
作为尽情K和输出决定性Ķ
then the property of when the arity
那么元数时的财产
States that if we have an input
国家，如果我们有一个输入
which is a linear combination up those inputs
这是一个线性组合起来这些输入
then the output is
然后输出
a linear combination of the Associated outputs
的相关输出的线性组合
so that linear combination of inputs
投入使线性组合
generates for linear system at the end output which is
在端输出，是生成用于线性系统
a linear combination up the Associated outputs now
线性组合起来美联社现在输出
the question is how can we exploit the properties have many arity
问题是我们如何能够利用属性有很多元数
and time-invariant and there's a basic strategy
和时间不变，并有一个基本策略
which will flow more or less through mostly this court's
这将流动或多或少大多通过这个法庭的
the strategy is to
该策略是
attempt to decompose the signal you the continuous-time and discrete-time
尝试将信号分解你的连续时间和离散时间
into it said a basic signals
把它说一个基本的信号
and I've indicated that
我已经表明，
here and the question then
这里的问题就
is what basic signal should we pick well
什么是基本的信号，我们应该挑好
the answer kinda is we should pick said a basic signals
答案还挺就是我们应该选择说一个基本的信号
they provide a certain degree have analytical convenience
它们提供了一定程度的具有分析的方便
so we choose instead of inputs for the decomposition
所以我们选择，而不是投入的分解
bad provide outputs
坏的产出提供
that we can easily generate now and we'll see
我们可以很容易地生成现在，我们将看到
when we do this there are to
当我们这样做有来
classes love inputs that are particularly suited
类爱输入，是特别适合
to that strategy one class is
该战略一类是
the set love the late impulses namely
集爱迟到的冲动，即
decomposing a signal into a linear combination if the
分解一个信号成线性组合，如果
is and as we'll see that leads to a representation
是和我们将看到导致的代表性
for linear time-invariant systems which is referred to
对于其被称为线性时不变系统
as convolution a second
卷积第二
is a decomposition of inputs into complex exponentials
是一个分解的投入复指数
a linear combination of complex exponentials
复指数的线性组合
and that leads to a representation
现象，导致一个表示
love signals and systems through what will refer to as
通过什么将称之为爱情信号与系统
for your analysis now
现在您分析
four-day analysis will be a topic for
4天的分析将是一个主题
a setup later lectures but I'd like to begin with
一个安装后的演讲，但我想首先
is the representation in terms of impulses and the associated description
是冲动方面的代表及相关说明
linear time-invariant systems using convolution
使用卷积线性时不变系统
so let's begin where
所以让我们开始的地方
a discussion are discrete-time signals
讨论是离散时间信号
and in particular the issue of how discrete-time signals
特别是离散时间信号是如何的问题
can be decomposed as a linear combination
可以分解为一个线性组合
love the lady impulses
爱小姐冲动
well in fact it's relatively straightforward
以及实际上它是相对简单的
what I've shown here is a general
我在这里显示的是一般的
sequence with values which i've indicated
序列我已经指示值
at the top and more or less
在顶部和更多或更少的
as we did when we talked about representing
与我们一样，当我们谈到较
a unit step in terms of impulses
在脉冲条件的单位步
we can think of this general sequence as a sequence
我们可以认为这种一般顺序为序
I'll impulses delayed
我会冲动延迟
namely occurring at the appropriate
即在适当的发生
prime instant and and with the appropriate ample to
素瞬间，并用适当的充足到
so we can think love this general sequence
所以我们可以认为爱这个一般顺序
as and im polls occurring at an equal 0
为和IM民调发生在一个平等0
and and with the high dive exit 0
并且，与高台跳水退出0
plus and im polls all quite active one
再加上和IM民调都比较活跃的地区之一
occurring at time n equals 1 and so that's active one time
在时间n发生等于1，所以这是活跃的一个时间
Delta than -1 and in polls at -1
达比-1，在投票调查中在-1
with an amplitude love exit -1
与振幅爱射-1
et cetera so if we continue
等等，所以如果我们继续
to generate a said Oh waited the late unit samples like that
生成一个说哦，等待后期单元样品一样，
and if we had all these together
如果我们把所有这些结合在一起
then that will generate the total sequence
然后，将产生的总序列
algebraically then what that corresponds to
代数那么对应于
is representing the sequence as
是代表序列
some love individual turns over as i've indicated here
有些爱个别翻转，因为我已经在这里表示
or in terms over general thumb
或计算，较一般的拇指
the song %uh exit K felt the then minus K
这首歌％呃K出口感受到当时零下Ķ
so that's our strategy the strategy is to decompose
所以这是我们的战略策略是分解
an arbitrary sequence into a linear combination
任意序列转换的线性组合
or waited too late impulses and here
或等待为时已晚的冲动，在这里
again is the representation which we just
再次是表示我们刚刚
finish generating
完成发电
now why is this representation useful
现在为什么是这种表示有用
it's useful because we now have a decomposition at the sequence
因为我们现在有一个分解的顺序是非常有用
as a linear combination all basic
作为一个线性组合的所有基本
sequences namely that the late impulses
序列，即已故的冲动
and if we are talking about a linear system
如果我们是在谈论一个线性系统
the response to that linear combination is a linear combination of the responses
响应该线性组合的响应的线性组合
so if we denote the response
因此，如果我们表示响应
to with the late in paul's as H+ the cave and
与已故的保罗的以H +的洞穴和
then the response to
然后将反应
this general input is what i've indicated here
这个一般的输入是什么，我在这里表示
where why event of course is the output
在那里，为什么，当然事件是输出
due to the general in protective and
由于在保护性的一般和
H+ the cave and is the output do
H +的洞穴，是输出做
to the late in polls and these are simply
到后期在投票调查中，这些都是简单的
the coefficients in the waiting
在等待的系数
so for linear system we have
所以对于线性系统，我们有
this representation and
这表示和
if now in addition the system is time-invariant
如果现在除了系统是时不变
we can in fact relate the outputs
我们其实是可以与输出
due to these individuals the late in polls
由于这些人在投票调查中后期
specifically if the system is time-invariant
具体地，如果系统是时不变
then the response to an impulse at the time
然后响应于一个脉冲在时间
K is exactly the same as the response to an impulse at time 0
K是完全一样的响应的脉冲在时间0
shifted over two-time K said another way
移过两次K说的另一种方式
h2k a van it simply
H2K一辆面包车它只是
80 then minus K where 80
80再减去K其中80
is the response to the system to an impulse at an equal 0
是响应于该系统的脉冲以相等的0
and it's generally useful to
并且它通常很有用
rather than carrying around 80 a band
而不是随身携带80带
just simply define 80 then
只是简单地定义80则
as a chip and which is
作为一个芯片和其
the unit sample or unit impulse response to the system
单位样品或单位冲激响应系统
and so the consequent then is for
所以随之而来的则是
a linear time-invariant system
一个线性时不变系统
the output can be expressed as this
的输出可以表示为这
some where a true then minus K
一些地方真正然后减去Ķ
is the response to an impulse occurring at time n equals K
为响应在时间n发生的冲动等于Ķ
and this is referred to
这被称为
as the convolution saw
作为卷积锯
now we can just to emphasize
现在我们可以只强调
how we've going about this let me show it from another perspective
我们如何去了解这个让我从另一个角度表现出来
we of course have taken the sequence X the van
当然，我们所采取的序列X面包车
we have decomposed that as
我们已经腐烂，由于
a linear combination out these waited the late impulses
线性组合这些等待后期的冲动
when these are added together those correspond
当这些加在一起的对应
to the original sequence active and
到原来的顺序激活和
if this in polls for example
如果这个民调为例
generates a response
生成响应
which is exit 0 times a chip and we're a tremendous the response
这是退出0次一筹，而我们是一个巨大的反应
to unit in polls at an equal 0
到单位调查以相等0
and the second one the late generates the delayed
而第二个后期产生延迟
waited response and the third one similarly
等待响应，第三个同样
and we generate these individual responses
我们产生这些个人反应
these are all added together and it that linear combination
这些都加在一起，它的线性组合
that forms the final output
形成最终的输出
so that's really kind of the way we're thinking about it we have a general
所以这是样的，我们正在考虑这个问题，我们有一个大致的方式真的
sequence
序列
we're thinking love each individual sample
我们正在考虑的爱每一个样本
individually each one of those pops the system
个别那些中的每一个弹出系统
and because the linearity the response is the sum
并且，因为线性的响应的总和
for those individual responses
对于那些个别的反应
well thats what happens in discrete-time and
以及多数民众赞成在离散时间发生的事情，并
pretty much the same strategy works in continuous-time
几乎同样的战略工作在连续时间
a particular
一个特定的
we can begin in continuous-time
我们可以在连续时间开始
with the notion 0 decomposing
与概念0分解
a continuous-time signal into
连续时间信号转换成
succession love are bitterly narrow rectangles
继承的爱情是苦涩窄矩形
and as these rectangles is the with the rectangles goes
和这些矩形是用那张矩形
0 the approximation gets better and
0近似变得更好，
essentially what's going to happen is that you to those individual rectangles
本质上发生了什么事情要发生的是，你的那些个人矩形
as they get narrower and narrower correspond more and more
因为他们得到窄对应越来越多
to an impulse well let me show you what I mean
一个很好的冲动让我告诉你我是什么意思
here we have a continue with time signal
在这里，我们有一个继续进行的时间信号
and I've approximated it
我已经接近了
by staircase
由楼梯
so in Athens I can't think of this
所以在雅典，我不能想到这